SCOTT R MCGANN



11833 Western Pine Road, Loch Lomond, CA 95461
Email whitehotrobot@gmail.com
Cell 707-328-6597

Objective

To acquire new skills, strive every day to establish and maintain reasonable standards, and work to forge and preserve prosperous working relationships with everyone.

Work Experience

Independent Contractor August 2020 – Present

Web Engineer

Continuous design and implementation of web solutions for open-source projects, including **Whitehot Robot**, a suite of tools for artists, musicians, authors, coders, and gamers.

https://codepen.io/cantelope. Project source is publically available @ srmcgann/whitehotrobot.com (github.com).

Tech stack: Vue.js, PHP, MySQL, bash scripting, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, & Linux.

Fowler Auto Center March 2020 – August 2020

Marketing Specialist

Managed website and digital footprint. Photography of vehicles. Implemented massive web based solution including tools for staff and customers to browse inventory, and interact with many aspects of digital content. Devised bidirectional data stream with inventory provider (<u>vAuto</u>) to localize control of inventory data and pricing, including management of online photography. Coordinated advertising and budgetary analysis of marketing into custom, interactive web-based reports.

Redwood Ford February 2019 – March 2020

Business Development Manager

Managed all internet sales leads. Tracked ROI for lead sources. Managed website and digital footprint. Photography of vehicles. Delivery of sold vehicles to customers, including review of technology and features. Made appointments and reported at manager meetings. Heavy phone and email marketing. Assisted all departments with operations. Installed 9 camera surveillance system. Performed as Facility Manager, in charge of overall dealership maintenance, surveillance system, and supervisor of the detail department. Assisted with interviewing applicants for the detail department. Oversaw detail dept. operations & schedule.

London Trust Media Holdings (LTMH) April 2018 – February 2019

Remote (work from home) Willits, CA -- Software Design / Full stack developer

Work primarily on Kiwi IRC (a communications platform and LTM subsidiary). Create web apps, plugins, HTML5 animations, support FOSS community. Work closely with small team of developers. Some marketing outreach work. Accomplishments: implemented Jitsi-meet as a plugin for embedded video conferencing. Created: custom client tool, emoji picker plugin, support for embedding Kiwi as a Vue component, countless bug-fixes.

Tech stack: Vue.js, WebPack/Babel, Node.js, PHP/Lumen/Laravel, HTML5, CSS, CSS3, Less, Git

Redwood Ford May 2017 – April 2018 Ukiah, CA 707-468-0091 Sales & Service

Started as a salesman. Sold new and used cars for 6 months then got promoted to Internet manager. Finally moved to the service department – became service writer/adviser. Provided IT support and web design.

Solid Wastes of Willits Inc. April. 2017 – July 2017 Willits, CA 707-459-4845

Temporary assignment - Mobile-Pak Setup

Worked with company's software (Soft-Pak) in conjunction with company's Mobile-Pak (e-Pak), to setup and integrate the programs to enable drivers to view route and customer service information via onboard computers, and provide real-time customer information to Office Customer Service staff. Trained drivers on use of Mobile-Pak while on routes, and trained office staff to integrate information, maintain and update mobile units.

Mendocino Coast Hospitality Center Feb. 2017 – April 2017 Fort Bragg, CA 707-961-0172 Analyst – Specialty Mental Health Clinic

Managed Database System (Exym). Scheduled appointments and tracked client signature renewal dates. Produced weekly reports for meetings indicating staff performance and department goal completion. Managed billing system, TARs (Treatment Authorization Requests), and Care Plan Cycles for clients. Assisted clients with intake paperwork. Performed filing, scanning and faxing duties.

Solid Wastes of Willits Inc. Oct. 2015 – Feb. 2017 Willits, CA 707-459-4845 Transfer Station Coordinator

Maintained volume and accounting records for 4 Recycle Centers and 8 Transfer Stations including reconciling site daily recycling and refuse volumes, cash payouts and receipts. Maintained cash on hand for all sites. Monitored, reconciled and investigated reporting and cash discrepancies at recycle centers and transfer stations. Performed weigh master duties and issued certified weight tags. This position required high level and extensive Microsoft Excel use, and use of software program Soft-Pak, Waste Management Software program.

Do It Once Consulting 2004 – 2013 Ukiah, CA 707-391-3749

CEO of IT Consulting Company

Webmaster, database manager, network administrator, and desktop support. Customers included Advance Power, Riveroak Charter School in Ukiah, the Hopland Band of Pomo Indians, and others.

ARG Enterprises (Black Angus Corporate Headquarters) 2003-2004 Los Altos, CA 800-382-3852 Programmer / IT Support

Provided IT support to restaurants and programmed menu changes. Used remote PC control software extensively. Worked in the corporate office.

Micros 2002-2003 Alameda, CA 510-749-0324

Implementation Specialist (programmer)

Staged POS (point of sale) systems. Programmed databases. Provided training and support to customers over the phone and via remote control software.

Summary of Qualifications

Twenty plus years of experience as a customer satisfaction specialist. Trainer, manager, designer, artist, coder, content-creator. Extensive experience in software and database implementation, network administration. Extensive knowledge of Microsoft Office programs, especially Execl. Typing (110 wpm). Team player – excellent collaborator.

Skills

Technology Summary

Tech stack: JavaScript/node, VueJS, Laravel/Lumen, WebPack, Less, PHP, MySQL, CSS, HTML/HTML5 Server Platforms: Linux & Windows

Education

High School: Bella Vista, Fair Oaks, CA Graduated 1994

American River College, Sacramento CA – Passed Geometry, Algebra, Trig

Yuba College Extension, Clearlake CA – Passed Biology, History, English 1A

Mendocino College, Ukiah - Earned units 2011-2012 - Computer Science major